Finding Aid for Washtenaw County Metropolitan Planning Commission publications, 1948-1980
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Washtenaw County Metropolitan Planning Commission publications 1948-1980
Washtenaw County Metropolitan Planning Commission
2 linear feet
2009134 Aa 2
Various publications of the Washtenaw County Metropolitan Planning Commission, also includes publications of the predecessor organization Washtenaw County Planning Commission.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The Washtenaw County Metropolitan Planning Commission publications were received as individual items or a parts of several accessions.
The publications are open without restriction.
Various publications of the Washtenaw County Metropolitan Planning Commission, also includes publications of the predecessor organization Washtenaw County Planning Commission.
Subjects:
Regional planning--Michigan--Washtenaw County.; Washtenaw County (Mich.)--Politics and government.; Washtenaw County (Mich.)--Economic conditions.; Washtenaw County (Mich.)--Population.
Contributors:
Washtenaw County Planning Commission.
- Serials
  - Annual report
    - 1949 (Box 1)
    - 1959 (Box 1)
    - 1960 (Box 1)
    - 1972 (Box 1)
    - 1973 (Box 1)
    - 1979 (Box 1)
- Non-serial publications
  - 1948
    - Washtenaw plans it's [sic] future (Box 1)
  - 1949
    - The industry of Washtenaw (Box 1)
  - 1951
    - A guide for subdivision of land (Box 1)
    - A plan for the development of the Ann Arbor-Ypsilanti metropolitan area (Box 1)
  - 1952
    - Washtenaw resource inventory: part I, study of agriculture (Box 1)
  - 1953
    - A guide for the subdivision of land in unincorporated areas of Washtenaw County, Mich. (Box 1)
    - A plan for the development of the Ann Arbor-Ypsilanti metropolitan area: recommended plan, part of Washtenaw County guide-plan (Box 1)
  - 1958
    - Huron River watershed--water management needs & problems (Box 1)
  - 1959
    - Ann Arbor Township capacities for development: preliminary report (Box 1)
  - 1960
    - A directory of cities, villages, townships county planning & zoning officials (Box 1)
      (Information bulletin, no. 2)
    - A park system for Washtenaw County (Box 1)
    - Why reconsider location of northwest by-pass, by Robert D. Carpenter (Box 1)
  - 1961
    - Labor force and employment projections for Washtenaw County, 1970 & 1980 (Box 1)
    - 1960 housing and population characteristics of Washtenaw County (Box 1)
    - Official planning commissions and zoning boards of Washtenaw County (Box 1)
    - Population change and projections for Washtenaw County, 1950 to 1980 (Box 1)
    - Population projections for civil divisions of Washtenaw County, 1970 & 1980 (Box 1)
  - 1962
    - Center of population, Washtenaw County and the Ann Arbor-Ypsilanti area (Box 1)
    - Directory, official planning commissions and zoning boards of Washtenaw County (Box 1)
    - A medical and health care facility study for Washtenaw County: preliminary report (Box 1)
    - Preliminary land use plan, Washtenaw County, 1980 (Box 1)
  - 1963
    - Industrial land plan tor Washtenaw County: a study outline (Box 1)
    - Preliminary review of a proposed comprehensive report of water supply and sanitary sewerage facilities for the County Planning Commission of Washtenaw County, Michigan, by Ayres, Lewis, Norris & May (Box 1)
    - A subdivision guide for preparing plats in township areas of Washtenaw County (Box 1)
  - 1964
    - Age and sex composition of population in Washtenaw County, 1950-1980, by T. Karl H. Wuersching (Box 1)
    - A capital improvement program for Washtenaw County
      - Part 1: Population, employment and income (Box 1)
        (preliminary draft)
    - Directory, official planning commissions and zoning boards of Washtenaw County (Box 1)
    - Mobile home park study (Box 1)
    - Suggested scenic routes for Washtenaw County (Box 1)
    - Washtenaw County, Michigan labor market--characteristics, forecast, and problems, by Gerard F. Carvalho (Box 1)
    - Washtenaw development goals: cities, villages, townships and county (Box 1)
  - 1965
    - A capital improvement program for Washtenaw County, by Harvey E. Brazer and others
      - Part 1: Population, employment and income (Box 1)
      - Part 2: Fiscal analysis of Washtenaw County government (Box 1)
      - Part 3: Capital needs and their financing: preliminary draft (Box 1)
      - Part 3: Capital needs and their financing (Box 1)
      - Part 3: Technical appendix (Box 1)
    - Economic trends influencing the Ann Arbor Township planning area: preliminary (Box 1)
    - Expressway route development plan: U.S. 23--Milan region, Michigan (Box 1)
    - 1990 land use space requirements within Ann Arbor Township planning area (Box 1)
    - Population analysis and projections, Ann Arbor Township: a preliminary report (Box 1)
    - Proposed official zoning ordinance for York Township, Washtenaw County, Michigan (Box 1)
    - Proposed zoning regulations for Augusta Township, washtenaw County, Michigan (Box 1)
    - Thoroughfare and sketch land use plans, Saline, Michigan: preliminary report (Box 1)
    - Washtenaw development goals: cities, villages, townships and county: conference proceedings, 30 September 1964 (Box 1)
  - 1966
    - Annotated bibliography of reports and studies (Box 2)
    - Directory: official planning commissions and zoning boards of Washtenaw County (Box 2)
    - Income from employment in Washtenaw County, Michigan, by Gerard F. Carvalho and George S. Odiorne (Box 2)
    - Occupational guides for Washtenaw County, Michigan (Box 2)
    - Preliminary report book one 1985 general development plan for Scio Township (Box 2)
    - Recent economic trends in Washtenaw County (Box 2)
      (Information bulletin, no. 1)
    - Report on water supply and sanitary sewage needs for Washtenaw County, Michigan: preliminary by Ayres, Lewis, Norris & May--McNamee, Porter & Seeley (Box 2)
    - Report on water supply and sanitary sewerage systems in Washtenaw County, Michigan, by Ayres, Lewis, Norris & May--McNamee, Porter & Seeley (Box 2)
  - 1967
    - Circulation in Ann Arbor Township (Box 2)
    - County parking study (Box 2)
    - Existing land use analysis for Ann Arbor Township (Box 2)
    - The first twenty years, 1947-1967 (Box 2)
    - Goals and objectives for Ann Arbor Township (Box 2)
    - 1990 potential demand for space within the Ann Arbor Township planning area (Box 2)
    - Preliminary 1985 general land use development plan for Pittsfield Township, Washtenaw County, Michigan (Box 2)
  - 1968
    - Annotated bibliography of reports and studies of the Washtenaw County Metropolitan Planning Commission, 1947-1968 (Box 2)
    - Capital improvement program for Washtenaw County (Box 2)
    - Part I: County facilities survey (Box 2)
    - Part II: Population forecast (Box 2)
    - County role in public works--background information (Box 2)
    - 1985 general land use development plan for Pittsfield Township, Washtenaw County, Michigan (Box 2)
    - Sheriff's Department study (Box 2)
    - Part I: Summary of findings (Box 2)
    - Part II: Background data (Box 2)
    - Washtenaw County data book (Box 2)
  - 1969
    - Ann Arbor Township, Michigan recommended general land development plan (Box 2)
    - Background information on the 1970 census (Box 2)
    - Capital improvement program for Washtenaw County
      - Part III: Personnel and fiscal analysis (Box 2)
      - Part IV: Needs, considerations and options (preliminary and final copies) (Box 2)
      - Part V: Recommendations: preliminary working draft (Box 2)
    - Directory: planning orientated officials from townships, villages, cities, county, and regional agencies of Washtenaw County (Box 2)
    - A policy approach to the development of a comprehensive park and open space system for Washtenaw County, Michigan (Box 2)
    - Washtenaw County data book. Rev. ed. (Box 2)
  - 1970
    - Washtenaw County planning directory (Box 2)
    - Annotated bibliography of reports and studies of the Washtenaw County Metropolitan Planning Commission, 1947-1969 (Box 2)
    - An inventory of recreational lands and facilities in Washtenaw County, Michigan (Box 2)
    - Land use code (Box 2)
    - Model subdivision regulation ordinance (Box 2)
  - 1971
    - Superior Township general development plan (Box 2)
    - Washtenaw County planning directory (Box 2)
  - 1972
    - Capital improvements program (Box 2)
    - Capital improvements program: summary (Box 2)
  - 1973
    - Economic activities of Washtenaw County (Box 3)
    - Initial housing element (Box 3)
    - Population of Washtenaw County, 1970 1980 & 1990 (Box 3)
  - 1974
    - Inventory of housing services (Box 3)
    - Planning perspectives on water resources: Washtenaw County, Michigan (Box 3)
    - Washtenaw County recreation and open space plan (Box 3)
  - 1976
    - Land use policies for Washtenaw County: preliminary (Box 3)
  - 1978
    - Land use policies for Washtenaw County: preliminary (Box 3)
    - Schematic design study, Old Post Office, Ann Arbor, Michigan (Box 3)
  - 1979
    - Agriculture in Washtenaw County: conditions, policies, and approaches to preservation (Box 3)
    - Washtenaw County household and population forecasts, 1970-2000 based upon the Washtenaw County Land Use Policies Plan (Box 3)
  - 1980
    - Report prepared for Central Area Action Program and Washtenaw County Metropolitan Planning Commission
      - Chelsea Village (Box 3)
      - Dexter Village (Box 3)
      - Milan City (Box 3)
      - Saline City (Box 3)
      - Whitmore Lake (Box 3)